visionexpress.com 2014-12-24

# Vision Express are registered with the Data Protection Registry - Visionexpress

﻿ 

Please read our Privacy and Cookie Policy carefully as this sets out how and why we collect personal information. By providing us with personal information you consent to the processing and transferring of personal information as set out in this Privacy and Cookie Policy.

For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is Vision Express (UK) Limited, Abbeyfield Road, Lenton, Nottingham, NG7 2SP, registered in England with company number 2189907

### General Provisions

Vision Express (UK) Limited is registered with the Data Protection Registry and takes its commitments and obligations under the Data Protection Act 1998 (and any subsequent legislation) and that of The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 very seriously.

Customer/User details are treated with the utmost respect and our staff are trained in the observance of the Data Protection Act.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy applies to any use of the Website and to any communications you may have with a Vision Express (UK) Limited store.

### Cookie Policy

  * What are cookies and how are they used?
  * How does visionexpress.com use cookies?
  * What cookies are used on visionexpress.com?
  * Third Party Cookies

Cookies are tiny text files stored on your computer when you visit certain web pages. At visionexpress.com we use cookies to remember useful information which allows certain functionality to work, such as shopping baskets or My Account access.

To order products from visionexpress.com or to access your My Account, you need to have cookies enabled. If you don’t wish to enable cookies, you’ll still be able to browse the site and use it for research purposes.

Please note that cookies can’t harm your computer. We don’t store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in cookies we create, but we do use encrypted information gathered from them to help improve your experience of our website.

We have relationships with carefully-selected and monitored suppliers who may also set cookies during your visit to be used for marketing-purposes – in other words to show you different products and services based on what you appear to be interested in. If you would like to opt out, please go to the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/index.asp) website (opens in a new window – please note we are not responsible for the content of external websites).

We're giving you this information as part of our initiative to comply with recent legislation, and to make sure we're honest and clear about your privacy when using our website. We know you'd expect nothing less from us, and please be assured that we're working on a number of other privacy and cookie-related improvements to the website.

The visionexpress.com website has a variety of useful features and tools, and to make best use of them your computer, tablet or mobile device will need to accept cookies. We can only provide you with certain features by using cookies, for example, to place orders (contact lenses or reserve & collect orders) on our website, it’s necessary to use cookies to remember your basket and promotions.

Our cookies don’t store sensitive information such as your name, address, date of birth or payment details: they simply hold the ‘key’ that, once you’re signed in, is associated with this information. However, if you would prefer to restrict, block or delete cookies from visionexpress.com, or any other website, you can use your browser to do this. Each browser is different, so check the ‘Help’ menu of your particular browser (or your mobile phone’s handset manual) to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

Below is a list of the cookies that may be stored on your computer when visiting visionexpress.com. From time to time we may make changes to this list as we introduce or remove functionality from our website.

Cookie Name | Cookie Purpose  
---|---  
Affiliate , _drt_ , id , __ar_v4 , ebNewBandWidth_.googleads.g.doubleclick.net , ysm_bbk1AEA18F4E6PD0VPCCVV7IPNE71G , svid , mojo2 , mojo3 , _mkto_trk , NETID01 , NETSEGS_ , rsi_segs_ , rtc_ , rsi_us , rsiPus , udm_ | This cookie shows us how you found our website and which website you came from. It also allows us to reward some external websites for directing you to us.  
Currentframe , spec , tryon_recentlist , tryon_shortlist  | Enable our Try-on service to temporarily remember which photo you have chosen/uploaded, which eyewear you have selected, and which eyewear you have assigned to your shortlist.  
Dynamic collapsible menu cookie | Allows our website to temporarily remember your refine selection when browsing our product catalogue, for example if you refine by a specific brand.  
fbs_ 284543134905885 , 284543134905885_user , 284543134905885_session_key , 284543134905885_ss , 284543134905885 , base_domain_284543134905885 | Enable our Virtual Try-on Tool to facilitate your login to Facebook and share images with your friends.  
Myvision_user , myvision_pass | When you log into My Account these cookies enable us to temporarily remember your username, and the fact that you have logged into My Account, so you don’t have to keep logging in during your visit.  
RecentProducts | Temporarily stores a shortlist of recent products you have viewed on our website.  
storeResultsPerPage , sort-dir , sort-limit , sort-sort , sort-page | These cookies assist our website with displaying products/store results, and remembering if you choose to see more/less products in one view.  
__utma , _utmb , __utmc , __utmz , __utmx , __utmxx , __utmx_k_159283811 , __utmx_k_264189141 , __utmx_k_170350201 | Collecting website statistics helps us understand website traffic and visitor activity. This provides us with information about how our site is being used and any errors, so we can make suitable improvements.  
webcamconfig | Enables our Try-on Service to identify if you have web-cam available and what the web-cam configuration is.  
VE_SESSION | Our website management system uses a number of cookies to make sure that pages load quickly and correctly for each visitor whether guests or registered users. Cookies are also used to ensure that each visit remains secure and that users are logged out after a period of inactivity.  
  
###### Flash cookies (or Local Shared Objects)

On visionexpress.com we display video content using Adobe Flash Player. Adobe uses Flash cookies (also known as Local Shared Objects) to help improve your experience as a user. Flash cookies are stored on your device in much the same way as usual cookies, but they're managed differently by your browser.

If you wish to disable or delete a Flash cookie, see Adobe Flashplayer Security Settings (opens in a new window). Please bear in mind though, that if you disable Flash cookies for visionexpress.com you'll unable to access certain types of content on the site, such as videos.

###### visionexpress.com 'share' tools

If you take the opportunity to 'share' visionexpress.com content with friends through social networks – such as Facebook and Twitter - you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

###### Further information about cookies

If you'd like to learn more about cookies in general and how to manage them, visit [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) (opens in a new window - please note that we can't be responsible for the content of external websites).

When you visit visionexpress.com you may notice some cookies that aren't related to Vision Express. If you go on to a web page that contains embedded content, for example from YouTube, you may be sent cookies from these websites. We don't control the setting of these cookies, so we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.

Some of the business partners that may set cookies on visionexpress.com include:

Partner Name | What cookies are used for  
---|---  
AudienceScience  
Google  
Mediaplex | Sometimes we'll advertise on 3rd party websites. Cookies from these sites are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements you click on and interact with. Each advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken is not confidential or interchangeable.

All of these 3rd party websites are part of the Network Advertising Initiative, which facilitates an opt-out list : <http://www.networkadvertising.org/index.asp>  
  
### Supply of personal information

When you shop, book appointments and/or enter competitions on this Website, we will ask you to input and will collect Personal Information from you such as your:

  * Name
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Billing address
  * Delivery address
  * Telephone number(s) – including mobile
  * Details of any prescription supplied to you by your healthcare professional or medical practitioner
  * Information you provide by filling in forms on the Website
  * Product selections
  * Details of your visit to the Website and any transactions you carry out on the Website

These are known as personal identifiers. We may in the usage of this Website require some or all of these personal identifiers to be deposited. Where such information is given, we are committed to protecting the privacy of the information received.

No information about you will be collected without your consent and you will be advised where personal information is called upon to be collected i.e. when you register for a particular service or order a product from us.

### Our use of your personal information

Your personal information will only be used for the purposes of processing your order; entering a Vision Express (UK) Limited competition; providing you with information on products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you (where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes); or as stated in this Privacy Statement and/or at the point of collection of the data.

By ordering through the Website you are required to register for online ordering and to accept the Terms and Conditions of Purchase. Please read the Terms and Conditions of Purchase carefully.

You expressly consent to Vision Express (UK) Limited:

  * Processing data relating to your credit/debit card and order details to enable to fulfilment of your order
  * Processing your personal information so that Vision Express (UK) Limited can inform you about new healthcare related products and services
  * Processing your personal information to enhance the services and goods Vision Express (UK) Limited makes available to its customers
  * Processing your personal data to conduct research about your health and shopping habits
  * Using cookies and traffic data

If you do not register as a customer but wish to email Vision Express (UK) Limited through the website ([customer.care@visionexpress.com](mailto:customer.care@visionexpress.com "Email customer care") ) you will be providing us with personal information about yourself, including your email address, name and contact details. This may include medical information. We will only use such information for the purposes of providing a reply, reviewing any feedback or improving the Website.

If you are simply browsing our Website we will not collect any personal information which will identify you, however, we will collect information using cookies and/or traffic data which uses IP addresses or other numeric identifiers which analyse navigation and use of the Website.

Personal information collected will be retained by Vision Express (UK) Limited for as long as is reasonably necessary (or defined under applicable healthcare laws and regulations) to provide products and services (including after sales service) to you.

### Disclosure to third parties

We will not pass your personal information to anyone outside of the Vision Express group of Companies (the “Group”) , without your prior consent, except the following:

  * Health authorities including NHS or national equivalent bodies; 
  * Third party service providers for the purpose of fulfilling your order; 
  * In the event that Vision Express (UK) Limited sells or buys any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer or seller; 
  * Any agents or subcontractors that process data on our behalf; 
  * Where we are otherwise legally required to do so (for example to the Inland Revenue, Benefits Agency, any court of competent jurisdiction or any law enforcement agency with statutory authority).

### Updating, accessing or removing personal information held by us

The Data Protection Act requires that information held about a Customer/User must be accurate and up to date. In the event that your details change (for example, in the event of marriage) or you move address it would be helpful if you could advise us of such a change so that your records can be updated.

You can amend or remove your personal details either by signing in to Your Account (if you are a registered online customer) or by notifying [customer.care@visionexpress.com](mailto:customer.care@visionexpress.com "Email customer care") .

You are entitled by law to request from us whether we hold any of your personal information and, if so, to request a copy of it. If you wish to exercise your data subject access rights, please contact us in writing with sufficient information to verify your identity and the personal information you require to: the Data Compliance Officer, Vision Express (UK) Limited, Abbeyfield Road, Lenton, Nottingham NG7 2SP. A £10 administration fee may be charged for complying with a subject access request and we shall provide such information within 40 days of your request.

In addition to requiring information to be up to date, the Act also provides that information should not be held or processed for longer than is necessary. You can therefore request that your details be deleted from our database at any time, although we would require written authority (or e-mail) from you in order to do this. Please note however that we are required by law to retain medical records for a statutory period of seven years after the conclusion of treatment.

### Marketing Material

We may use your personal information to contact you in relation to healthcare related products and services offered by Vision Express. To ensure that you continue to receive excellent healthcare, Vision Express (UK) Limited will send you non-marketing material such as appointment reminders and notices to remind you of the expiration of your current prescription.

You can opt out of receiving marketing communications from Vision Express (UK) Limited at anytime by notifying the Data Compliance Officer in writing (or by e-mail at [e-business@visionexpress.com](mailto:e-business@visionexpress.com "Email Vision Express e-business") ) and we will action your request.

Having opted in to receive email marketing material you will always be provided with an opportunity to opt out on every communication, in accordance with The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

### Not a past or present customer?

If you are not a past or present customer of Vision Express, you will have been sent an acquisition mailing. The data company Equifax provide information to companies such as ourselves for direct marketing purposes, so we can contact potential customers with details of the products and services we provide. The data we have acquired from them has been collated from sources such as the Royal Mail data files and the Electoral Roll register.

If you do not wish to receive acquisition mailings from us, please contact our Data Compliance Offer in writing, at the address below, or by email to [e-business@visionexpress.com](mailto:e-business@visionexpress.com "Email Vision Express e-business") . We will require your first name, surname, postcode, and ideally date of birth to ensure we can correctly identify your record and cease mailing activity.

We will then contact Equifax on your behalf to stop any future mailings being sent to you by Vision Express in this way.

If you wish to stop prospective mail from all companies, not just Vision Express, we advise you to join the MPS ([Mail Preference Service](http://www.mpsonline.org.uk/mpsr/)) register. Details for this are available online and you can sign up anytime. Please remember to update your details with MPS if you move house or change name.

### Disclaimer

We are committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorised access and use. As effective as modern security practices are, no physical or electronic security system is entirely secure. We cannot guarantee the complete security of our database, nor can we guarantee that information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet. Any transmission is at your own risk. In the event that there is an interception of your personal information or unauthorised access or use of our database, we will not be liable or responsible for any resulting misuse of your personal information.

We have no control over the contents of third party sites or resources which are linked to the Website and we accept no responsibility or liability for them or the privacy practices they use or for any loss or damage that may arise from your use of such websites or resources.

### Updating our Privacy and Cookie Policy

We may update this Privacy and Cookie Policy from time to time in our sole discretion and, in such event, we will post a clear message on our Website. By continuing to use the Website after we post notification of any such changes, you accept and agree to this Privacy and Cookie Policy as modified.

### Contacting us

Vision Express (UK) Limited has appointed a Data Compliance Officer to ensure compliance on all Data Protection issues. The Data Compliance Officer can be contacted by writing to Vision Express (UK) Limited, Abbeyfield Road, Lenton, Nottingham NG7 2SP. Any queries or concerns should be addressed in the first instance to the Data Compliance Officer.

Last Updated: May 2012

### Legal notices and website information:

  * User Conduct and use of website
  * Intellectual Property Rights
  * Freedom of Information Act 2000
  * Legal Disclaimer
